Finding Aid for the Donald Spoto Papers LSC.1563
UCLA Library Special Collections
Donald Spoto papers
circa 1940-1988
UCLA Library Special Collections
Spoto, Donald, 1941-
LSC.1563
17 linear feet (34 boxes and 6 oversize boxes)
Donald Spoto (1941- ) wrote biographical studies of film and theater personalities. The collection contains files relating to Spoto's biographies and includes books, magazines, interviews, bibliographies, holograph notes, cassette recordings, film scripts, letters, and galley proofs covering the lives of Tennessee Williams, Alfred Hitchcock, Lotte Lenya, Preston Sturges, and Laurence Olivier. Spoto's doctoral dissertation and two of his original screenplays are included as well.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
CONTAINS AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: This collection contains both processed and unprocessed audiovisual materials. For information about the access status of the material that you are looking for, refer to the Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note at the series and file levels. All requests to access processed audiovisual materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Donald Spoto, 1988-92.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9932222343606533
Biography
Spoto was born June 28, 1941 in New Rochelle, New York; BA, Iona College, 1963; MA (1966) and Ph.D. (1970), Fordham University; taught at New School for Social Research, New York City, 1975-86; began teaching at University of Southern California in 1987; visiting lecturer, British Film Institute, National Film Theatre, London, 1980-86; published biographical studies of filmmakers Stanley Kramer, Alfred Hitchcock, Preston Sturges, playwright Tennessee Williams, and actors Marlene Dietrich, Marilyn Monroe, Lotte Lenya, Laurence Olivier, Elizabeth Taylor, Ingrid Bergman, and James Dean.
Scope and Content
Collection contains files relating to Spoto's biographies of film and theater personalities. Research material is organized first by personality, then by work. Includes books, magazines, interviews, bibliographies, holograph notes, cassette recordings, film scripts, letters, and galley proofs covering lives of Tennessee Williams, Alfred Hitchcock, Lotte Lenya, Preston Sturges, and Laurence Olivier. Also includes Spoto's doctoral dissertation and two of Spoto's original screenplays.
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
Series 1. Biographical
Series 2. Tennessee Williams
Series 3. Alfred Hitchcock
Series 4. Lotte Lenya
Series 5. Preston Sturges
Series 6. Laurence Olivier
Series 7. Screenplays
Items Removed from Collection
Books Removed for Cataloging:
Leavitt, Richard F. The world of Tennessee Williams. With an introduction by Tennessee Williams. New York: G.P. Putnam's Sons, c. 1978. First edition, signed by Richard Freeman Leavitt and Tennessee Williams. Copy number: 226/250.
Leavitt, Richard Freeman, comp. and ed. Ave atque vale! memorial pages preserving the final notices.. .of Tennessee Williams. 1983?. Limited edition.. .copy number 7.. .is presented to Dakin Williams.
Van Antwerp, Margaret A., and Sally Johns, eds. Tennessee Williams. Afterword by Louis Auchincloss. Detroit: Gale Research Company... c. 1984. A Bruccoli Clark book. Dictionary of literary biography, documentary series, an illustrated chronicle, vol.4.
Williams, Tennessee. It happened the day the sun rose. Los Angeles, Sylvester & Orphanos, 1981. Copy 95 of 350.
Motion picture producers and directors -- Research.; Motion picture actors and actresses -- Research.; Authors, American -- 20th century -- Archives.; Olivier, Laurence; Spoto, Donald, 1941- --Archives.; Sturges, Preston.; Williams, Tennessee 1911-1983.; Hitchcock, Alfred; Lenya, Lotte
- Biographical, Series 1
  - Christ's preaching to the dead: an exegesis of I Peter 3,19 and 4,6., 1970. (Box 10, Folder 3)
    Scope and Content
    Spoto's dissertation for the degree of Doctor of Philosophy in the Department of Theology at Fordham University.
- Tennessee Williams, Series 2
  - Books
    - Wood, Audrey, with Max Wilk. Represented by Audrey Wood. Garden City: Doubleday., 1981. (Box 12)
    - Williams, Tennessee. Where I live: selected essays. Edited by Christine R. Day... [New York]: New Directions., circa 1978. (Box 12)
    - Williams, Tennessee. The night of the iguana. 5th printing. [New York]: New American Library., circa 1961. (Box 12)
      Scope and Contents note
      Annotations.
    - Williams, Tennessee. Eight mortal ladies possessed: a book of stories. 2nd printing. New York: New Directions, 1973. (Box 12)
    - Williams, Tennessee. In the winter of cities. New York: New Directions., 1964. (Box 12)
    - Yacowar, Maurice. Tennessee Williams on film. New York: Frederick Ungar., circa 1977. (Box 12)
    - Williams, Tennessee. The knightly quest: a novella and four short stories. [New York]: New Directions., circa 1966. (Box 12)
    - Williams, Tennessee. Cat on a hot tin roof. 5th printing. New York: New Directions., circa 1975. (Box 12)
    - Williams, Edwina Dakin. Remember me to Tom. St. Louis: Sunrise., circa 1963. (Box 12)
    - The Tennessee Williams newsletter. [vol.1 no.1], vol.1 no.2, vol.2 no.1-2, vol.3 no.2., 1979 Spring (Box 12)
      Minor annotations.
    - Hirsh, Foster. A portrait of the artist: the plays of Tennessee Williams. Port Washington, New York: Kennikat Press, 1979. (Box 12)
    - Bowles, Jane. Feminine wiles. Introduction by Tennessee Williams. Santa Barbara: Black Sparrow Press., 1976. (Box 12)
    - Williams, Tennessee. A streetcar named desire. With an introduction by the author. [New York]: New American Library. 21st printing., circa 1947. (Box 12)
    - Tharpe, Jac, ed. Tennessee Williams: 13 essays. Jackson: University Press of Mississippi., 1980. (Box 12)
      Holograph note by DS in back of book.
    - Maxwell, Gilbert. Tennessee Williams and friends: an informal biography. Cleveland and New York: the World Publishing Company, 1965 (Box 13)
      Minor annotations. Inscribed: For Irwin T. Holtzman, sincerely, Gilbert Maxwell, New York, May 4, 1966.
    - Williams, Tennessee. One arm. 5th printing. [New York]: a New Directions book., undated (Box 13)
    - Weales, Gerald. Tennessee Williams. Minneapolis, University of Minnestoa Press. University of Minnesota pamphlets on American writers., circa 1965. (Box 13)
      General note
      (Catalog[?] / Gifts)
    - Williams, Tennessee. Camino real. [New York]: a New Directions book., 1970 (Box 13)
    - Williams, Tennessee. Clothes for a summer hotel: a ghost play. [New York]: a New Directions book, 1983. (Box 13)
    - Williams, Tennessee. Moise and the world of reason. New York: Simon and Schuster, 1975.; Lacks dust jacket. (Box 13)
    - Williams, Tennessee. Androgyne, mon amour. Second printing. [New York]: New Directions, 1977. (Box 13)
    - Williams, Tennessee. Vieux Carre. Third printing. [New York]: New Directions., circa 1979. (Box 13)
    - The Franklin Library. Notes from the editors: Tennessee Williams, selected plays. Franklin Center, Pennsylvania: The Franklin Library., circa 1981. (Box 13)
    - Williams, Tennessee. American blues: five short plays. Acting edition. [New York]: Dramatist's Play Service, Incorporated., undated (Box 13)
    - Windham, Donald, ed. Tennessee Williams' letters to Donald Windham 1940-1965. (Box 13)
      Edited and with comments by Donald Windham. New York: Holt, Rinehar.
      Gifts.
    - Steen, Mike. A look at Tennessee Williams. New York: Hawthorn Books, Incorporated, publishers., circa 1969. (Box 13)
    - Vidal, Gore. Matters of fact and of fiction (essays 1973-1976). New York: Vintage Books, 1978. (Box 13)
    - Londre, Felicia Hardison. Tennessee Williams. Third printing. New York: Frederick Ungar Publishing Company, 1983. (Box 13)
    - Gotham Book Mart & Gallery, Incorporated. Tennessee Williams, a catalogue., circa 1980s (Box 14)
    - Williams, Tennessee. Hard candy: a book of stories. Sixth printing. [New York]: a New Directions book., undated (Box 14)
    - Williams, Tennessee. Stopped rocking, and other screenplays. With an introduction by Richard Gilman. [New York]: a New Directions book., circa 1984. (Box 14)
    - Falk, Signi. Tennessee Williams. Second edition. Boston: Twayne Publishers [1978]. (Box 14)
      Two pages annotated.
    - Gunn, Drewey Wayne. Tennessee Williams: a bibliography. Metchuen, New Jersey and London: the Scarecrow Press, Incorporated. Scarecrow author bibliographies., 1980. (Box 14)
    - Williams, Dakin. The bar bizarre. Edited by Lucy Freeman. n.p., circa 1980. (Box 14)
      Inscribed: with best wishes, Dakin Williams.
    - Williams, Tennessee. Memoirs. Garden City, New York: Doubleday and Company., circa 1975.; Lacks dust jacket. (Box 14)
    - Stanton, Stephen S. Tennessee Williams: a collection of critical essays edited by Stephen S. Stanton. Second printing. Englewood Cliffs, New Jersey., undated (Box 14)
    - Williams, Dakin, and Shepherd Mead. Tennessee Williams, an intimate biography by his brother. New York: Arbor House., circa 1983. (Box 14)
    - The theatre of Tennessee Williams. vol.1-7. [New York]: a New Directions book, 1978-1981. (Box 15)
      Various printings for the individual volumes. Annotations. vol.1-4 this box. Remaining volumes in Box 16.
    - Williams, Tennessee. Baby doll, the script for the film, Something unspoken, Suddenly last summer. Penguin Books...., 1976. (Box 16)
    - Rader, Dotson. Tennessee: cry of the heart. Garden City, New York: Doubleday & Company, Incorporated., 1985. (Box 16)
    - McCann, John S. The critical reputation of Tennessee Williams, a reference guide. Boston: G.K. Hall & Company., circa 1983. (Box 16)
    - The theatre of Tennessee Williams. vol.5-7. (Box 16)
  - Spoto's research material
    - Interviews and obiter dicta. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Bibliographies. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Family background and history to: TW Chapter 1., 1911 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - TW:, 1930-1935. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - TW:, 1935-1940. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - TW:, 1940-1945. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - TW:, 1945-1950. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - TW:, 1950-1955. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - TW:, 1955-1960. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - TW:, 1960-1965. (Box 1, Folder 10)
      1965-1970 material found here and following next file.
    - TW:, 1970-1975. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - TW:, 1975-1980. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - TW:, 1980-1983. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - San Domenico Palace Hotel, Taormina, Sicily. Brochures, etc. (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Tennessee Williams 70 [birthday celebration greetings, photocopies in printed folder]. (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Holograph notes from unidentified source., In spiral notebook. (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Cassette recordings: interviews, programs, etc. (Box 24, Box 25)
      Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
      CONTAINS AUDIO MATERIALS: Materials will require assessment and may need further processing for safe access. Please contact Special Collections reference (spec-coll@library.ucla.edu) for more information.
    - Cassette recordings, microfilm of bibliography. (Box 26)
  - Plays
    - Something cloudy, something clear, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      With cover letter from Eve Adamson to TW, 1981 September 3 (photocopy).
    - Something cloudy, something clear. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Stopped rocking., 1977. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - All Gaul is divided, a teleplay based on A lovely Sunday for Creve Coeur., 1979 June. (Box 3, Folder 4)
      First draft.
    - The remarkable rooming-house of Mme. Le Monde. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - This is (an entertainment). (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - The Red Devil battery sign, a work for The Presentational Theatre., 1976 September. (Box 3, Folder 7)
      With program from the Phoenix Theatre.
    - Will Mr. Merriwether return from Memphis?, 1969. (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - A house not meant to stand, a Gothic comedy., 1982 April 27. (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Clothes for a summer hotel. (Box 3, Folder 10)
      Revised March 14.
    - Clothes for a summer hotel, a ghost-play in 4 scenes., 1979 April-September. (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Now the cats with jeweled claws., 1983 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Alfred Hitchcock, Series 3
  - Biographical information
    - 1899-1925 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - 1925-1935 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - 1935-1940 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - 1940-1945 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - 1945-1950 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - 1950-1955 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - 1955-1960 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - 1961-1965 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - 1966-1970 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - 1971-1980 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Books
    - Tutti i film Hitchcock a cura di Riccardo Rosetti. [Milano]: Savelli editori, 1980. (Box 22)
    - Leff, Leonard J. Hitchcock and Selznick, the rich and strange collaboration... New York: Weidenfeld & Nicolson, 1987. (Box 22)
      Uncorrected proof, in wrappers.
    - Haley, Michael. The Alfred Hitchcock album. Englewood Cliffs, New Jersey, Prentice-Hall, Incorporated, 1981. (Box 22)
    - Cameron, Ian, ed. Movie reader. New York and Washington: Praeger Publishers, 1972. (Box 22)
    - Harris, Robert A. and Michael S. Lasky. The films of Alfred Hitchcock. Secaucus, New Jersey: the Citadel Press, 1976. (Box 22)
      Inscribed: Jan 31, 1977, for Donald Spoto - a fellow Hitchophile - with warmest regards Bob.
    - Rothman, William. Hitchcock - the murderous gaze. Cambridge and London: Harvard University Press., 1982. (Box 22)
    - Taylor, John Russell. Hitch, the life and times of Alfred Hitchcock. New York: Pantheon Books, 1978. (Box 23)
    - Camera / stylo. Alfred Hitchcock., 1981 November. (Box 23)
    - Durgnat, Raymond. The strange case of Alfred Hitchcock, or, the plain man's Hitchcock. Cambridge: the MIT Press [1974]. (Box 23)
    - LaValley, Albert J., ed. Focus on Hitchcock. Englewood Cliffs, New Jersey: Prentice-Hall, Incorporated [1972]. (Box 23)
    - Phillips, Gene D. Alfred Hitchcock. Boston: Twayne Publishers., 1984. (Box 23)
    - Simsolo, Noel. Hitchcock. Cinema d'aujourd'hui 54. [Paris]: Editions Seghers, 1969.; Leaves are coming unglued from binding. (Box 23)
    - The Alfred Hitchcock movie quiz book. [New York]: Perigree Books, 1986. (Box 23)
    - Brown, Bryan. The Alfred Hitchcock movie quiz book. [New York]: Perigree Books, 1986. (Box 23)
    - Rohmer, Eric and Claude Chabrol. Hitchcock, the first forty-four films. Translated by Stanley Hochman. New York: Frederick Ungar Publishing Company, 1979. (Box 23)
    - Freeman, David. The last days of Alfred Hitchcock, a memoir.. .Woodstock, New York: the Overlook Press, 1984. (Box 23)
    - Perry, George. The films of Alfred Hitchcock. Highgate Hill and New York: Studio Vista / Dutton, 1970. (Box 23)
      Reprinted from c. 1965.
  - Spoto's research material
    - Letters, obiter dicta, interviews, speeches, articles by. (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Funeral details, obituaries, tributes, etc. (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Bogdanovich () and Freeman () on AH., 1963 1982 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous theory and criticism, notes. (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Criticism: articles on AH, to 1970. (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Bibliographies, microfiche. (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Family: Alma, Pat, early English period. (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Criticism: articles, to 1950. (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Criticism: articles, to 1980. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Articles on AH's work (file B). (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Bogdanovich on AH. (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Journals with articles about AH. (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Notes on individual films. Copyright by Donald Spoto., 1979; ca. 100 leaves. (Box 10, Folder 2)
      Typescript[?].
    - Storyboards for Family plot., 1975. (Box 11)
      Prepared by illustrator Tom Wright, given to DS by AH 1975 November [oversize box].
    - Press books, etc. for: Rebecca, Frenzy, The Birds, Rear Window, etc. (Box 11)
    - Cassette recordings (Box 26)
  - Spoto's research material by movie
    - The pleasure garden. (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - The mountain eagle. (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - The lodger. (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Downhill. (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Easy virtue. (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - The ring. (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - The farmer's wife. (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Champagne. (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - The manxman. (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Blackmail. (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Juno and the paycock. (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Murder! (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - The skin game. (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Number seventeen. (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Rich and strange. (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Waltzes from Vienna. (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - The man who knew too much. (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - The 39 steps. (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Secret agent. (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Sabotage. (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Young and innocent. (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - The lady vanishes. (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Jamaica Inn. (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Rebecca. (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Foreign correspondent. (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Mr. and Mrs. Smith. (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Suspicion. (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Saboteur. (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Shadow of a doubt. (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Lifeboat. (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Bon voyage and Aventure malgache. (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Spellbound. (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Notorious. (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - The Paradine case. (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Rope. (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Under Capricorn. (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Stage fright. (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Strangers on a train. (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - I confess. (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Dial 'M' for murder. (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Rear window. (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - To catch a thief. (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - The trouble with Harry. (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - The man who knew too much. (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - The wrong man. (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Vertigo. (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - North by northwest. (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - No bail for the judge. (Box 6, Folder 3)
      Written but unproduced.
    - Psycho. (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - The birds. (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Marnie. (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Torn curtain. (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Topaz. (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Frenzy. (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Family plot. (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Scripts
    - The short night., 1979 March 2. (Box 10, Folder 6)
      Working draft by David Freeman.
    - The short night., 1978 June 27. (Box 10, Folder 7)
      Screenplay by Ernest Lehman.
    - The 39 steps. (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - The lady vanishes. (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - The man who knew too much. (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Rebecca. (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Suspicion. (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Saboteur. (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Shadow of a doubt. (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Lifeboat. (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Spellbound. (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Notorious. (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - The Paradine case. (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Rope. (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Strangers on a train. (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Dial 'M' for murder. (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Rear window. (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - To catch a thief. (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Vertigo. (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - North by northwest. (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Psycho. (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - The birds. (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Marnie. (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Torn curtain. (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Frenzy. (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Family plot. (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Mary Rose., 1963. (Box 21, Folder 5)
      First draft of unproduced screenplay.
- Lotte Lenya, Series 4
  - Book by James K. Lyon: Bertolt Brecht in America, 1982 (Box 22)
  - Manuscript: Lenya: a life, circa 1989; Little, Brown and Company (Box 11)
    Photocopy of galley proofs[?]
  - Manuscript: Lenya: a life, 1988 June (Box 27, Folder 2)
    Fourth and final draft.
  - Manuscript: Lenya: a life, 1989 April (Box 27, Folder 3)
    Uncorrected advance proof.
- Preston Sturges, Series 5
  - Spoto's research material
    - Miscellaneous articles from journals and newspapers., Photocopies. (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Mary Desti. The untold story., Photocopy. (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Sturges., 1898-1958
      - 1898-1910, 1910-1920. (Box 28, Folder 3)
      - 1920-1925. (Box 28, Folder 4)
      - 1927. (Box 28, Folder 5)
      - 1928. (Box 28, Folder 6)
      - 1929. (Box 28, Folder 7)
      - 1930 January-June. (Box 28, Folder 8)
      - 1930 July-December. (Box 28, Folder 9)
      - 1931. (Box 28, Folder 10)
      - 1932. (Box 28, Folder 11)
      - 1933. (Box 29, Folder 1)
      - 1934. (Box 29, Folder 2)
      - 1935. (Box 29, Folder 3)
      - 1936-1937. (Box 29, Folder 4)
      - 1938. (Box 29, Folder 5)
      - 1939. (Box 29, Folder 6)
      - 1940. (Box 29, Folder 7)
      - 1941. (Box 29, Folder 8)
      - 1942. (Box 29, Folder 9)
      - 1943. (Box 29, Folder 10)
      - 1944. (Box 29, Folder 11)
      - 1945. (Box 29, Folder 12)
      - 1946. (Box 29, Folder 13)
      - 1947. (Box 29, Folder 14)
      - 1948. (Box 29, Folder 15)
      - 1949. (Box 29, Folder 16)
      - 1950. (Box 29, Folder 17)
      - 1951. (Box 29, Folder 18)
      - 1952. (Box 29, Folder 19)
      - 1953. (Box 30, Folder 1)
      - 1954. (Box 30, Folder 2)
      - 1955. (Box 30, Folder 3)
      - 1956. (Box 30, Folder 4)
      - 1957. (Box 30, Folder 5)
      - 1958. (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - Cassette recordings of interviews (Box 31)
  - Manuscript: Madcap: the life of Preston Sturges, 1989 March 13 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Manuscript: Madcap: the life of Preston Sturges, 1989 June (Box 27, Folder 1)
    Second draft.
  - Manuscript: Madcap: the life of Preston Sturges, 1989 June (Box 31, Folder 1)
- Lawrence Olivier, Series 6
  CONTAINS AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: This collection contains both processed and unprocessed audiovisual materials. For information about the access status of the material that you are looking for, refer to the Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note at the file levels. All requests to access processed audiovisual materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
  - The Old Vic - The Story of a Theatre, 1983 (Box 40, Folder 24)
    Commercially produced tape.
  - Interviews by Spoto
    - Lawrence Olivier at the Oscars, 1979 (Box 39, Folder 1)
      Includes Robert Fry interview (1990).
    - Gerry Pinciss on Olivier and Shakespeare, 1990 (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - John Schlesinger and Ben Benjamin interviews for Olivier, 1990 (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - Memorial service for Olivier, 1989 (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - BBC-TV special on Olivier, 1984. (Box 39, Folder 5)
      This is comprised of 2 cassettes with a four-part interview. Tape no.2 includes 60 Minutes (1982) Olivier interview.
    - Sunny Lash, 1990 (Box 39, Folder 6)
      - Sunny Lash, 1990 March 8; yrlsc_1563_039_06a; Spoto, Donald, 1941-; Lash, Sunny; 1 Sound Recordings (1 audiocassette; Duration: 0:47:41) (Box 39, Case 6)
        CONTAINS AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: Audiovisual materials are available for access. All requests to access digital materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
        Scope and Contents
        Transcribed from container: "Interview at her home, LA"
      - Sunny Lash, 1990 March 8; yrlsc_1563_039_06b; Spoto, Donald, 1941-; Lash, Sunny; 1 Sound Recordings (1 audiocassette; Duration: 0:24:27) (Box 39, Case 6)
    - Charlton Heston and Daniel Petrie, 1990 (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - Jean Simmons and Richard Fleischer, 1990 (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - Anthony Crickmay and Rachel Kempson Redgrave, 1989 (Box 39, Folder 9)
    - Michael Redington and Harold Kasket, 1989 (Box 39, Folder 10)
    - Morgan-Jumel (conclusion only) and Gwen Ffrangcon-Davies, 1989 (Box 39, Folder 11)
    - Joyce Howard and Basil Langton, 1990 (Box 39, Folder 12)
    - Elaine Dundy and Gerry Pinciss, 1990 (Box 39, Folder 13)